prosafe.com 2019-09-24

# Privacy Policy | Prosafe

**Privacy Statement for Prosafe SE**

This privacy statement represents the online privacy policy applicable to [www.prosafe.com](http://www.prosafe.com/) and its online activities. The statement explains how we collect, use and disclose information when you use our website.

 **Prosafe (“we”** and **“us”),** is the controller of personal data processed in connection with our website.

### How we collect and use personal data

 **Visitors to our website**

When you visit [www.prosafe.com](http://www.prosafe.com/) we collect data through cookies. The data we collect through cookies consist of data relating to your device, IP-address and your use of the website. We use the data collected through cookies for providing you with the best user experience and for improving the website’s content by tracking usage patterns and recording preferences. This information is only processed in a way which does not identify the person visiting the website.

 **Subscribers to newsletters**

When you subscribe to receive a newsletter (which may include news, press releases and stock exchange notifications from Prosafe), we collect your e-mail address in order to be able to send you the requested newsletter. In order to subscribe, you must provide your consent prior to receiving the newsletter. You can opt-out of receiving newsletters from us at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of the newsletter that you receive. By doing so, you will have withdrawn your consent to us processing your data for this specific purpose.

 **Customers**

In order to provide our customers the services they require from us, Prosafe collects and stores business-to-business contact information, such as name, company name, phone number, e-mail address, title and department name. We also store exchanged communication, preferences or feedback that is important to meet your requirements as a customer.

 **Suppliers**

Prosafe stores business contact information necessary to process invoices, payments or other commitments with suppliers, agents or other parties. In connection with the selection process, we collect due diligence information, which may include company structure, credit checks, references, interviews and other background checks.

 **People who contact and visit us**

When you contact us in relation to projects, media or investor contacts, supplier relations or sponsorships, we collect your name, e-mail address and phone number and any other information that you wish to provide to us in order to enable us to meet your request. 

In some offices, we collect your name, name of employer and name of the person you are visiting when you visit our offices through our visit registration system. We use this data for notifying the person you are visiting about your arrival and for security reasons and in case of an emergency situation.

 **Job applicants**

We collect data necessary to assess the suitability of candidates for employment at Prosafe, such as personal contact details, previous experience and education, and other information such as job certificates, work permit, references and other relevant background information. If you are shortlisted, we may further collect tests and results of background checks. If Prosafe makes a final offer, we will also ask for other details needed to administer your employment with us such as bank details and emergency contact details.

### Prosafe’s processing of personal data

 **Our legal basis for processing**

Prosafe will always process personal data fairly and lawfully, and only for a specified, explicit and legitimate purpose or as required by law. Prosafe will ensure appropriate information security related to confidentiality, integrity and availability. 

Prosafe will only process personal data where there are legal grounds to do so. Most commonly, we will process your personal data: (i) in order to fulfil a contract with you or in pursuit of entering into a contract with you; (ii) where required by law; or (iii) where it is in our legitimate interests to do so (and those interests are not overruled by your own rights).  Our legitimate interests are listed above under “How we collect and use personal data” and concern our wish to constantly improve our website, establish a professional and collaborative relationship with you, provide our business services and respond to any queries you may have for us. The legal basis for processing your e-mail address when you subscribe to a newsletter is your consent, which you are free to withdraw at any time.

Unless you are notified otherwise, we will not use profiling, or automated decision making in any form, to make important decisions that will affect you.

 **Sharing of personal data**

Prosafe will not share your personal data with third parties except for in circumstances where such sharing is necessary as part of our regular operation or to provide our services as further described in this section.

Third party service providers, including providers of IT services may process personal data on behalf of Prosafe. Prosafe will implement adequate safeguards in accordance with applicable law to protect your personal data processed by third party service providers.

We will not disclose your personal data to third parties for the purposes of allowing them to market their products or services to you.

 **International transfers of personal data**

When sharing personal data to other parties, we sometimes need to transfer personal data to a country outside the European Union (EU) or the European Economic Area (EEA) in order to be able to fulfil one of the purposes set out in this Privacy Statement. As an example, we may need to transfer personal data to a Prosafe company outside the EU/EEA in order to be able to offer you a job if you have applied for a position outside of the EU/EEA.

We will not transfer personal data to a third country outside of the EU/EEA that does not provide adequate protection of personal data unless appropriate safeguards are adduced or the transfer otherwise takes place in accordance with applicable data protection legislation. Examples of such safeguards are Binding Corporate Rules, EU Standard Contractual Clauses or if the receiving party is certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield.

 **Cookies**

As noted above, the Prosafe website uses cookies to ensure you get the best user experience. Cookies are small text files that are placed on your device to track usage patterns and record preferences. Our cookies do not contain information that can identify persons. Prosafe gives an explicit notice when entering the website [www.prosafe.com](http://www.prosafe.com/) that we use cookies. If you continue browsing, we assume you accept the use of cookies.  You can set your browser not to accept cookies. 

Cookie Settings

 **Security of processing**

We will process your personal data securely and will apply and maintain appropriate technical and organisational measures to protect your personal data against accidental or unlawful destruction or accidental loss, alteration, unauthorised disclosure or access, in particular where the processing involves the transmission of data over a network, and against all other unlawful forms of processing. Access to personal data is strictly limited to personnel of Prosafe, its direct or indirect subsidiaries at all levels and its third party contractors referenced above who have appropriate authorisation and a clear business need for that data.

 **Retention and deletion of data**

Your personal data will be retained as long as necessary to fulfil the legitimate purpose(s) for the processing and as long as required by law. It will then be destroyed. If you or your employer have a contractual relationship with us, any personal data relating to you will be retained as long as necessary to enable us to fulfil our obligations relating to that contractual relationship.

If you apply for a job, we will retain your personal data for one year from when the position is filled, and delete it thereafter, unless you request us to retain it for a longer period of time in order to notify you of similar job offerings. If you consent to certain processing, we store your personal data until you withdraw your consent or once the personal data is no longer necessary for achieving the purpose of the processing.

 **Your rights as a data subject**

You have the right to request access to, rectification of or erasure of any information we have collected about you through your use of the website and its online functionalities. You can also object to or request the restriction of our processing and withdraw your consent to processing where it is relied upon. To help us keep your personal data updated, we advise you to inform us of any changes or discrepancies.

To exercise your rights as a data subject, or if you wish to make a complaint regarding our compliance with this Privacy Statement, please contact the Director – People & Organisation at Prosafe on [databreach@prosafe.com](mailto:databreach@prosafe.com)

You have a right to complain to the relevant Supervisory Authority, for example the Norwegian Data Protection Authority or the Information Commissioner’s Office in the United Kingdom, but we encourage you to first contact the Director – People & Organisation before filing such complaint.

 **Privacy statements of third parties**

This Privacy Statement addresses the collection, use and disclosure of personal data by Prosafe as described above. This Privacy Statement does not address or govern the privacy practices adopted by third parties on third party websites or in relation to third party services that may be accessible through use of the website.

Although we try only to link to websites that share our high standards for privacy, we are not in any way responsible for the content or the privacy practices employed by third party websites or third party services. We encourage you to familiarise yourself with the privacy policies applicable to such websites or services prior to providing them with your personal data.

 **Governing law and jurisdiction**

The www.prosafe.com website is governed by Norwegian law, and the District Court of Oslo shall be the legal venue with exclusive jurisdiction over any dispute arising from your use of this website.

 **Changes to this privacy statement**

We may update this Privacy Statement from time to time. If such updates are minor and do not have a material meaning for your rights or the way we use personal data, we may make such changes without posting a specific notice on our website. We encourage you to review this Private Statement on a regular basis to familiarise yourself with the latest updates.

If we make material changes to this Privacy Statement that may affect your rights or the way we use personal data, we will notify you accordingly.

 **How to contact us**

If you have any questions or comments relating to this Privacy Statement or want to exercise your rights, please send an email to [privacypolicy@prosafe.com](mailto:privacypolicy@prosafe.com) You can also contact us at Prosafe AS, P.O. Box 39 Forus, N-4064 Stavanger, Norway
